# AHMED ABDELMONEM

# **MOBILE DEVELOPER (REACT-NATIVE, EXPO)**

+201068368002 | ahmedabuelenin17@gmail.com | Portfolio | Github | LinkedIn

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced mobile developer with 4 years in mobile apps development. Proficient in JavaScript, Typescript, React Native and Expo. Developed and deployed various apps successfully, some achieving thousands of downloads. Eager to apply my skills to drive excellence and innovation at your company.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Expo Developer, Self-Employed

Sep 2024 - Present (3mos)

- Developed The Great Quran app.
- · Designed app UI/UX with Figma.
- · Deployed app to Google Play Store.
- · Technologies: typescript, expo, expo-router, expo-sqlite, ...etc

# React Native Developer, Squadio (Contract)

**Jan 2024 - May 2024** (5mos)

- Worked on FANCY and FANCY partner, a solution to provide beauty services.
- Refactored code, fixed bugs, added new features, enhanced perform and UX.
- Technologies: typescript, react-native, REST APIs Integration, git, react-hooks, react-navigation, react-query, google services, firebase, ...etc

### React Developer, Self-Employed

Mar 2023 - April 2023 (2mos)

- Created an e-commerce web app of multiple pages for selling fashion stuff.
- Created a portfolio of my production mobile apps.
- Technologies: html5, css3, js, react, sass, react-router-dom, react testing library, etc

#### React Native Developer, High High app (Full Time)

Nov 2021 - Feb 2023 (1 yr 4 mos)

- Worked on HighHigh app, an innovative solution for content advertising.
- Refactored code, fixed bugs, added new features, enhanced perform. and UX.
- Shipped app to play store and app store.
- Technologies: typescript, react-native, REST APIs Integration, git, react-hooks, redux, firebase, google services, Paypal and In-App Purchase integrations, ...etc.

#### React Native Developer, Upwork (Freelance)

Oct 2021 (1 mo)

- Worked on PiggyPag app, a solution for reducing flying trip fees.
- Added new features, fixed bugs and integrated Stripe payment.
- Shipped app to play store.
- Technologies: typescript, react-native, REST APIs integration, git, react-hooks, react-navigation, redux, yup, formik, ...etc

# React Native Developer, Fudex EBS (Full Time)

Oct 2020 - Sep 2021 (1 yr)

- · Worked on retail, delivery, beauty and job search apps some created from scratch and others collaborated on with my team members.
- Created reusable, maintainable and testable components
- · Shipped apps to app store.
- · Technologies: javascript, react-native, REST APIs integration, git, react-hooks, reactnavigation, redux, firebase, google services, ...etc

## Android Developer, Ipda3 Tech (Internship)

Feb 2020 - Apr 2020 (3 mos)

- Created two apps Sofra and BloodBank from scratch.
- Integrated app with back-end through REST apis.

#### **SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES**

<ul> <li>Problem So</li> </ul>	lving
--------------------------------	-------

React

• Git

SQLite

Firebase

XCode

• CI/CD • HTML

Javascript

React-Native

Redux

React-Navigation

Google Services

Stripe

Jest

• CSS

Typescript

Expo

React-Query

· React-Hook-Form

· Android Studio

In-App Purchase

Testing Library

SASS

#### **EDUCATION**

**BSc**, Electrical Engineering

Cairo University

2010

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

• Languages: Arabic, English